<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on Associated Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Surgeons</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on Associated Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Surgeons</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3-D Imaging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/3d-imaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/3d-imaging/</guid>
      <description>Dental cone beam CT, also known as CBCT, is a specialized imaging technique that provides highly detailed 3D images of the oral and maxillofacial structures. Unlike traditional dental X-rays, which capture only two-dimensional views, CBCT offers a comprehensive view of the teeth, jawbone, and surrounding tissues.&#xA;Using a cone-shaped X-ray beam that rotates around the patient&amp;rsquo;s head, CBCT captures multiple cross-sectional images. These images are then reconstructed by powerful software to create a three-dimensional representation of the oral anatomy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apicoectomy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/apicoectomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/apicoectomy/</guid>
      <description>Apicoectomy, also known as root-end surgery, is a dental procedure that involves removing the tip of the tooth&amp;rsquo;s root and surrounding infected tissue. It is typically performed when a conventional root canal treatment fails to alleviate the infection or when there are complications in reaching the tip of the root through traditional methods.&#xA;When Is an Apicoectomy Recommended? One common reason for recommending an apicoectomy is when there is persistent pain and swelling around the affected tooth despite previous attempts at treatment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bone Grafting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/bone-grafting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/bone-grafting/</guid>
      <description>Bone grafting is a dental procedure that involves replacing or augmenting missing bone in the jaw. Bone loss can occur as a result of tooth extraction or periodontal disease. When teeth are removed, the surrounding bone can deteriorate over time. This can lead to problems with neighboring teeth and compromise the overall structure and stability of the jawbone.&#xA;If you&amp;rsquo;re considering dental implants to replace missing teeth, having sufficient bone density is crucial for successful implantation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canine Exposure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/canine-exposure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/canine-exposure/</guid>
      <description>Canine exposure is a crucial dental procedure that aims to guide unerupted canines into their correct positions in the dental arch. By working with our skilled surgeons at Associated Oral &amp;amp; Maxillofacial Surgeons, patients experiencing issues with these teeth can find relief and improve their oral health.&#xA;Common Issues With Unerupted Canines Unerupted canines, also known as impacted canines, occur when these crucial teeth fail to emerge properly from the gum line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dental Implants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/dental-implants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/dental-implants/</guid>
      <description>Dental implants are advanced restorative solutions that replace missing teeth by surgically implanting biocompatible titanium posts into the jawbone, serving as artificial tooth roots. These implants provide a stable foundation for various prosthetic restorations, such as crowns, bridges, or dentures, restoring both functionality and aesthetics to the smile. With benefits including improved chewing ability, jawbone structure preservation, shifting teeth prevention, and long-term durability, dental implants offer a permanent and natural-looking solution for individuals seeking to regain confidence and oral health following tooth loss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facial Fractures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/facial-fractures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/facial-fractures/</guid>
      <description>A facial fracture is a break or crack in the bones of the face. The human face is composed of multiple interconnected bones, including the jawbone (mandible), cheekbones (zygomatic bone), nose, and eye sockets (orbital bones). These delicate structures are susceptible to injury due to various factors such as accidents, falls, sports-related incidents, or physical altercations.&#xA;The severity and location of facial fractures can vary greatly depending on the force and angle of impact.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facial Trauma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/facial-trauma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/facial-trauma/</guid>
      <description>Facial trauma in dentistry refers to injuries sustained to the face, jaws, and oral structures due to various incidents like accidents, falls, sports injuries, or assaults. These injuries can include fractures, dislocations, soft tissue lacerations, and damage to teeth and surrounding tissues. Prompt treatment of facial trauma in dentistry is crucial for several reasons. It helps to alleviate pain, prevent infection, and minimize the risk of long-term complications such as tooth loss, malocclusion, and temporomandibular joint (TMJ) disorders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frenectomy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/frenectomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/frenectomy/</guid>
      <description>The frenum, a crucial component of the oral cavity, can be described as a delicate mucus membrane fold that functions to connect either the lip to the gums or the tongue to the floor of the mouth. This specialized membrane primarily consists of connective tissue fibers and lacks any muscle fibers.&#xA;The presence of these connective tissue fibers facilitates proper attachment between different parts of our mouth while ensuring stability and flexibility during various oral movements such as speaking, eating, and swallowing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full Mouth Reconstruction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/full-mouth-reconstruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/full-mouth-reconstruction/</guid>
      <description>Full mouth reconstruction involves comprehensive dental treatments to rebuild and restore all teeth in the upper and lower jaws. This extensive process can include a combination of procedures such as crowns, bridges, veneers, dental implants, and orthodontics to address functional issues like bite alignment and oral health problems such as tooth decay and gum disease. The benefits of full mouth reconstruction are substantial, offering improved oral function, enhanced aesthetics, and significant relief from pain or discomfort caused by damaged or missing teeth.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immediate Implant Placement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/immediate-implant-placement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/immediate-implant-placement/</guid>
      <description>Immediate implant placement (IIP) in Frederick, Hagerstown, and Martinsburg is a modern dental technique that involves placing a dental implant into the jawbone immediately after tooth extraction. This means that instead of waiting for weeks or months to heal before receiving an implant, patients can have the implant placed right away.&#xA;Immediate implant placement offers several advantages over traditional implant techniques, allowing patients to regain their smiles faster and more efficiently while maintaining optimal oral health.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implant-Supported Dentures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/implant-supported-dentures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/implant-supported-dentures/</guid>
      <description>Implant-supported dentures, also known as implant-retained dentures or overdentures, are a modern dental solution designed to provide stability and functionality for individuals who have lost most or all of their natural teeth. Unlike traditional removable dentures that rely on suction or adhesive for support, implant-supported dentures are anchored securely in place by dental implants.&#xA;Dental implants are titanium posts that are surgically placed into the jawbone beneath the gums. These posts act as artificial tooth roots, providing a strong foundation for attaching the denture prosthetic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lip Tie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/lip-tie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/lip-tie/</guid>
      <description>Lip tie is a condition where the thin band of tissue connecting the upper lip to the gum line is unusually tight or thickened, potentially restricting the movement of the upper lip. This can lead to challenges with breastfeeding in infants, difficulty forming a proper seal around a bottle or breast, and may contribute to dental issues and speech difficulties in older children and adults. Treating lip ties through procedures like frenotomy or frenuloplasty can improve breastfeeding success, promote proper oral development, and enhance speech clarity, ultimately leading to improved oral health and overall well-being.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Dental Implants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/multiple-dental-implants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/multiple-dental-implants/</guid>
      <description>Multiple dental implants are a restorative dental solution that replaces several missing teeth. This procedure involves surgically placing two or more titanium posts into the jawbone, each serving as a stable anchor for individual crowns, a bridge, or even a full set of dentures. The benefits of multiple dental implants are substantial: they offer a permanent, natural-looking, and functional replacement for missing teeth, improving aesthetics and oral functionality. Unlike traditional dentures or bridges, multiple implants provide superior stability and prevent bone loss by stimulating the jawbone, thus preserving facial structure and preventing the sunken appearance that often accompanies tooth loss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oral Pathology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/oral-pathology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/oral-pathology/</guid>
      <description>Oral pathology refers to the specialized field of dentistry that focuses on the study, diagnosis, and treatment of diseases affecting the oral cavity. It involves examining various conditions that can occur in the mouth, such as infections, tumors, cysts, and other abnormalities.&#xA;The oral cavity is a complex structure composed of different tissues and organs like the lips, tongue, gums, salivary glands, and throat. Just like any other part of our body, these structures are susceptible to diseases and disorders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platelet-Rich Plasma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/platelet-rich-plasma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/platelet-rich-plasma/</guid>
      <description>Platelet-rich plasma, commonly known as PRP, is a cutting-edge treatment that has gained popularity in recent years. PRP involves using a patient&amp;rsquo;s own blood to extract platelets and plasma. Platelets are tiny cells responsible for clotting and healing damaged tissues, while plasma is the liquid portion of blood containing important growth factors.&#xA;How Does It Work? To create PRP, a small amount of blood is drawn from the patient and then placed in a centrifuge machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sedation Dentistry</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/sedation-dentistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/sedation-dentistry/</guid>
      <description>Sedation dentistry, also known as sleep dentistry or twilight dentistry, is a technique used to help patients feel relaxed and at ease during dental procedures. It involves the use of medication that induces a state of deep relaxation or even sleep, depending on the level of sedation required. At our dental office, all services that need IV sedation are rendered under the supervision of doctors specialized in providing IV sedation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Implants</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/single-implants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/single-implants/</guid>
      <description>A single dental implant is a modern dental solution designed to replace an individual missing tooth. It involves the surgical insertion of a titanium post into the jawbone, which acts as a replacement for the tooth root. This post is topped with an abutment, which connects the implant to a custom-made crown that mimics the appearance and function of a natural tooth. The benefits of a single dental implant are extensive: it provides a natural look and feel, restores full chewing power, and enhances speech.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tongue Tie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/tongue-tie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/tongue-tie/</guid>
      <description>Tongue tie, medically known as ankyloglossia, is a condition present at birth where the lingual frenulum, the tissue connecting the tongue to the floor of the mouth, is abnormally short, thick, or tight. This restriction can limit the tongue&amp;rsquo;s range of motion, impacting various functions such as speaking, swallowing, and breastfeeding. Symptoms of tongue-tie may include difficulty sticking out the tongue, challenges with breastfeeding or latching onto a bottle, speech difficulties, and oral hygiene issues.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom Tooth Removal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/wisdom-tooth-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/omax-website/services/wisdom-tooth-removal/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom teeth, also known as third molars, are the last set of molars located at the back of the mouth. Most people have four wisdom teeth – two in the upper jaw and two in the lower jaw. These teeth typically emerge in late adolescence or early adulthood, usually between the ages of 17 and 25.&#xA;The name &amp;ldquo;wisdom teeth&amp;rdquo; is derived from the fact that they emerge during a time in life when an individual is assumed to be older and wiser.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
